<resources>

    <string name="app_name">KarpinskiDonskoy</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="jacek_karpinski">Jacek Karpinski</string>
    <string name="karpinski_desc">Polish pioneer in computer engineering and computer science. During WW2 he was a soldier of Batalion Zośka of Polish Home Army, awarded multiple times with a Cross of Valour. Among the others he took a part in Operation Kutschera (intelligence) and Warsaw Uprising when he was heavily wounded. Later he became a developer of one of the first machine learning algorithms, techniques for character and image recognition. After receiving a UNESCO award in 1960, he studied for 2 years at Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Harvard University. In 1971 he designed of one of the first minicomputers, the K-202. Because of the policy on computer development in the People\'s Republic of Poland, belonging to the Comecon that time, K-202 was never mass-produced. Karpiński later became a pig farmer, and in 1981, after receiving a passport, emigrated to Switzerland. He also founded the Laboratory for Artificial Intelligence of the Polish Academy of Sciences in the early 1960s.</string>
    <string name="mikhail_donskoy">Mikhail Donskoy</string>
    <string name="donskoy_desc">He was a Soviet and Russian computer scientist. In 1970 he graduated from Moscow State University and joined the Institute of Control Sciences of the USSR Academy of Sciences, where he became one of the lead developers of Kaissa, a computer chess program that won the first World Computer Chess Championship in 1974. After the dissolution of the Soviet computer chess initiative in the beginning of 1980s he went into development of databases. In 1994 he established his own company, DISCo (Donskoy Interactive Software Company), which, among other projects, developed the Symbian interface for ABBYY Lingvo dictionaries.</string>

</resources>
